

Rajeev Singh Chandel

GIS Specialist with a demonstrated working experience in the GIS industry. It is important for me to keep thinking unique and be inspired by modulation of changes happening in the GIS industry, in return for it I do my best to use it in my work

- Mouse No. 159/A, Hanumantpuram, Raebareli, Uttar Pradesh - 229001
- +91-9450467866, +91-9511548891
- rajeevchandelsingh@gmail.com
- © 03/12/1990
- Marital status Unmarried
- Languages English, Hindi

EDUCATION

P.G. Diploma in Remote Sensing and GIS 2015-2016

Banaras Hindu University

Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh

M.B.A. 2008-2010

Gautam Buddh Technical University

(G.B.T.U. Formerly U.P.T.U.),

Greater Noida Institute of Technology

Greater Noida

Chhatrapati Shahu Ji Maharaj

2005-2008 University (C.S.J.M.U.),

Kanpur

12th(CBSE) 2005

K.B.A.Sr.Sec. School

Raebareli, Uttar Pradesh

10th(CBSE) 2003 K.B.A.Sr.Sec. School

Raebareli, Uttar Pradesh

I.I.R.S. - CERTIFICATION PROGRAMME

Apr 2018 Geoinformatics for Forest Fire

Management

Mar 2018

Hyperspectral Remote Sensing

and its Applications

Jan 2018 Close Range Photogrammetry

and terrestrial Laser Scanning

Dec 2017 Overview of RS and GIS Applications

for Natural Resource Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2019-Present Jaipur, Rajasthan

G.I.S. Expert Yashi Consulting Services Pvt. Ltd.

G.I.S. Executive May 2016-Jan 2019

Ceinsys Tech Ltd. Jaipur, Rajasthan

G.I.S. Executive Sep 2013-Jun 2015

Skylark Designer & Engineers (P)

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Services & Sales Executive Jun 2010-Sep 2013

Acme Digitek Solutions (P) Ltd.

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

SOFTWARE SKILLS

MS Office

Arc GIS **ERDAS Imagine QGIS** AutoCAD Map 3D **IDRISI Selva** Arc Earth Google Earth Lumen RT Adobe Photoshop Arc City Engine 3D

PRIME PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

Yashi Formulation of GIS Based Master Plan for 17 AMRUT Consulting Cities/Towns in Harvana

Services (ACTIVITY PERFORMED- Street Coding, Utility Mapping, Pvt. Ltd. QC of Survey Form Check, Drone Image Checking, Block Boundary Making, Rectification of Land Base Data, Digitization of the Imagery Provided, etc.)

Ceinsys GIS Based Asset Mapping & Land Base creation of 33

Tech Ltd. District. Raiasthan

(ACTIVITY PERFORMED- Creating Road Network database; Creating Rail-Road database including Metro; Capturing POI database of all Government Assets and other important amenities; Integration between Land Base, POI and Govt. asset. etc.)

Skylark Railway Network database for East Central Railways (ACTIVITY PERFORMED- Digitization of Geo-referenced

map, Query Building and Attribute fill up, Shape Area & Shape Length Calculation, Perform spatial queries such as intersects, etc.

PRIME ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Dissertation 2016

P.G. Diploma A Remote Sensing & GIS Based Study of Hydrological Inferences of Koshi River (Bihar) for Water Resource Management

> Link to access - https://issuu.com/rajeevsinghchandel/docs/ final_dessertation_rajeev_et_al.

PUBLISHED RESEARCH PAPERS

2018 "Use of Geospatial Techniques to Manage the Tourists & Administration: A Case Study of Mount Abu, Rajasthan.", Environ. We Int. J. Sci. Tech. 12, ISSN: 0975-

7120, Vol. 13, No. 1, pp. 63-78.

Link to access - https://www.researchgate.net/publication/326560213_Use_of_ Geo-Spatial_Techniques_to_Manage_the_Tourists_Administration_A_Case_Study_of_Mount_Abu_Rajasthan

2018

"Hydrological Inferences through Morphometric Analysis of Lower Kosi River Basin of India for Water Resource Management based on Remote Sensing Data.", Applied Water Science, Springer Journals, ISSN:

2190-5487, Vol.8.

Link to access - https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs13201-018-0660-7

+ 4 more Research Papers

SEMINARS ATTENDED / PRESENTED PAPERS

5th Annual International Conference on "Challenges & Solutions for a Sustainable Environment"

> Presented Research Paper on "Use of Geospatial Techniques to Manage the Tourists & Administration: A Case Study of

Mount Abu, Rajasthan."

Aug 2013 International Conference on "Tradition Wisdom & Modern Knowledge for Earth's Future", Kyoto International

Conference Center (ICC), Kyoto, Japan.

Aug 2013 International Conference on "Regional Diversity and

Campus, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan

a Possibility of collaboration in East Asia", Hakozaki

+ 7 more Seminars

PERSONAL SKILLS

Smart and Hard Working

Leadership Team work

Time management

Decision making

Client Handling

Co-ordination & Co-operation

WORKSHOPS

Feb 2019 Use of Super Map GIS

at Center for Climate Change & Water Research, SGVU, Jaipur

May 2018

Hydro-metrological Disaster One Day online Workshop

Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO)

TECHNICAL COGNIZANCE

Arc GIS Geo-referencing, Digitization of Geo-referenced map, Query Building and Attribute fill up, Code Matching of Government Assets, POI checking, Categorization of POI Data as per client requirement, Spatial Adjustment (Attribute Transfer), GDB Up-dating & Matching Government assets with codes as per client requirement, Grid Formation, Fishnet Creation, Masking & Converting into KML, Geo-Database Mak- ing with proper schema, Shape Area & Shape Length Calculation, Perform spatial queries such as intersect, nearest, buffer, Preparation of Relief, Slope, Aspect, Contour and TIN map from Dem Data, Perform Supervised Classification approach, Lay- out creation of digitized map etc.

ERDAS Imagine Data Import process, Layer Stacking, Data Subset, Data Mosaic process, Geo-referencing of Topgraphical Map, Map to Map, Map to Imagery, Imagery to Imagery etc., Supervised Classification approach, Principal Component Analysis (PCA), Resolution merge of high resolution pan data and multispectral LISS 3 data, Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI), Normalized Difference Water Index (NDWI), Spatial filtering etc.

Quantum Geo-referencing, Digitization of Geo-referenced map using Point, Line & **GIS** Polygon features etc.

REFERENCES

Mr. Sahadev Roy

Project Manager Cenisys Tech. Ltd. Jaipur, Rajasthan Tel.-+91-9887096943

e-mail - sahadev.roy7@gmail.com

Dr. K.N.P. Raju,

Professor Dept. of Geography, Institute of Science, B.H.U. Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh

Tel.- +91-9935346553

e-mail - knpraju1954@gmail.com

Dr. Prayeen Kumar Rai.

Assistant Professor Dept. of Geography, Institute of Science, B.H.U. Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh Tel.- +91-9452783001

e-mail - bhu.praveen22@gmail.com

Mr. Surendra Singh

Assistant Project Manager Yashi Consulting Services Pvt. Ltd. Jaipur, Uttar Pradesh Tel.- +91-8743057990

e-mail - surendra@yashiindia.com

Mr. Amit Kumar Srivastava,

Manager, Diaitek House. Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh Tel - +91-8009090025

e-mail - amit.srivastava@acmedigitek.com